DENIS COUTO

Senior Cloud Engineer and Architect

+55 11 95043-8225
Brazilian
denis.couto@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/deniscouto/ | about.me/docouto







I am a seasoned professional with more than two decades in the field. Experienced in designing, deploying and technical delivery in small and large enterprise environments. Solid experience on a wide range of solution stacks.

Skills & Expertise

- Extensive knowledge of Microsoft Stack (onprem and Azure).
- Solid knowledge in automation tools such as PowerShell, Terraform and Ansible.
- Solid knowledge of Linux administration.
- Solid knowledge software delivery processes and tooling. containers, and tools such as Azure DevOps, Octopus Deploy, Kubernetes.

Certifications

Azure: DevOps ExpertCCA-V: Citrix Certified Associate-VirtualizationAzure: Administrator AssociateCC-VAD-CC: Citrix CVAD Service on Citrix

MCSE: Cloud Platform and Infrastructure Cloud

Professional Experience

Duosystem, São Paulo, Brazil

SRE / Cloud Architect

2023 - Present

Member of the Cloud Architecture team, I have been helping the company to solidify their path into Cloud, especially Azure, establishing standards and governance to achieve solid long-term results. To this point, I was able to help with:

- Assess the company's cloud footprint, which led to:
 - Bring costs down about 30%/year by eliminating shadow IT, orphan resources, deprecated resources, establishing common SKU for similar workloads, consolidating workloads in the cloud and back on-prem where required.
- Architect and deploy Cloud Ingress based on Azure Front Door, Azure Application Gateway and WAF
 policies to deliver applications hosted both on Azure and on-prem, which brought in:
 - Increased application reliability.
 - Secure application delivery.
 - Higher performance due to load balancing and caching.
- Consolidate 3rd party app authentication using SSO with Azure Entra ID, which helped with:
 - Ease the onboarding/offboarding process.
 - Secure company's data against data exfiltration.
- Plan and migrate from AWS to Azure an in-house digital healthcare product. Running on top of Azure Kubernetes and Azure Functions on a Hub&Spoke architecture, which led to:
 - Consolidation of sparse unmanaged microservices under one governed Cloud.
 - Set the standard on how the company orchestrate containers.
 - Ramping up teams' technical knowledge.
- Led sessions with US based Microsoft Fast Track team, helping the team to get insights and learn best practices to modernize the main company product.
- Write and troubleshoot Azure DevOps Classic/Yaml Pipelines for App and IAC deployments.
- Write and troubleshoot Terraform code targeting Azure.
- Lead the planning and implementation of a multi subscription landing zone for a datacenter migration.
- Knowledge sharing of new standards and ways of doing Cloud infrastructure through brown bag type sessions, Wiki articles and writing Standard Operating Procedures (SOP).
- Day to day Cloud operations.

Citrix Systems, Dublin, Ireland

Senior Escalation Engineer

2018 - 2022

Working in the EMEA Escalation team, I provided analysis of complex problems in a 24x7 follow the sun support environment.

In-Depth knowledge of *Citrix DaaS* and Citrix Cloud (Azure based), leveraging debugging techniques to manage high severity cases which could be politically or technically challenging.

Day to day used to go by:

- Leveraging a variety of tools to get to the bottom of issues. Tools like Splunk, Azure CLI, Powershell.
- Reading and correlating code on Sourcegraph to customers issues.
- Analysis of memory dump with WinDBG.
- Deep engaging with Product Engineering trough Jira and Slack for further troubleshooting.
- Mentoring and delivering training sessions to Frontline engineers on how to leverage Powershell with Citrix Products.
- Writing public KB articles with workarounds or fixes mapped to features releases.
- Leading the managing and distribution of the load across a pool of senior engineers.

#Citrix #DaaS #Azure #Identity #Engineering #Debugging #Splunk #Powershell

Ergo Group, Dublin, Ireland

Level 3 Support Engineer

2015 - 2018

Working on escalation/BAU tasks for several customers (Aercap, CIE, Goshawk, AerLingus, Dunbia and many others) managing a variety of products and services, such as: Windows Server, Linux, Azure, Office 365, Hyper-V, VMware ESXi, Netscaler, Xenapp and others.

Also worked on a dedicated team for a high value customer going beyond BAU tasks I had the opportunity to automate a series of tasks through Powershell using functions and modules that helped to:

- Finding details of servers combining data from AD, Solarwinds and VMware.
- Finding and gathering important details of dozens of SQL Server instances.
- Enabling employees to have their pictures synced across different company's tools.
- Wrapping 3rd party DMS APIs to better integration with LOB applications.

For this same customer I was the go-to person for their CD solution based on *Octopus Deploy*, orchestrating with a 3rd party vendor the deployment and availability of their main application.

#Level3 #Citrix #Virtualization #Azure #Powershell #Octopus #Elastic #Linux #Ansible

DoMore! Soluções em Produtividade, São Paulo, Brazil

2009 - 2015

Senior Microsoft Infrastructure Engineer

- Planning, deploying, and managing medium to large SharePoint farms and applications for companies like Odebrecht, Vale, PWC, Pfizer, Carrefour and others.
- Administering internal and Azure infrastructure running several Microsoft solutions such as Hyper-V, SharePoint (2007,2010, 2013), Office 365, SQL Server, Visual Studio Team Services.

#SharePoint #Engineering #Powershell

Atento Brasil, São Paulo, Brazil

2006 - 2008

Level 3 Server Support Engineer

- Performing 3rd level support to Windows environment with more than 10.000 users and 12 locations nationwide.
- Managing VMware ESXi and Microsoft network products, Exchange Server 2007

#Level3 #Windows #Virtualization

SSI Consultoria, São Paulo, Brazil

2004 - 2006

Server Administrator

- Managing a Windows network environment and SQL Server together with Visual Source Safe.
- Managing Linux (Red Hat) Iptables Firewall, Web Proxy with Squid and reports with SARG.

#SysAdmin #Windows #Linux #Firewall #Proxy

Languages

- Portuguese Native
- English Fluent

Education

Faculdade Eniac, Guarulhos, São Paulo Computer Networking 2002 - 2004